A Guide to the American Society of International Law records, Howard M. Holtzmann papers FA1872
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Writings, II; 15.66 Cubic Feet 29 legal document boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
  - Other Writings, 1974-2012; 2
    - Powers of Arbitrators Under United States Law to Fill "Gaps" Arising Under Long-Term Commercial Contracts, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Proposed Multi-Lingual Arbitration Glossary, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Questions Concerning the Desirability and Text of the UNCITRAL Project to Improve Planning of Arbitral Proceedings, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "The Reason for the Project", undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "Recent Developments at UNCITRAL", 2002 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "Recent Legislation that Combines Conciliation and Arbitration", 1994 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - "Recent Work on Dispute Resolution by the United Nations Commission on International Trade Law", 1999 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Remarks at Commencement of College of Nursing and College of Health Related Professions, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - "Remuneration of Arbitrators, Introductory Notes", 1970 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - "The Second Annual Yale Jewish Alumni Forum - Remarks of Judge Howard M. Holtzmann", 1992 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Setting Aside Arbitral Awards - The Common Law Viewpoint", 1989 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Settlement of Investment Disputes, undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Speech Material, 1988-1992 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Speech Material, 1951-1958 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Statement to Eleventh Session of UNCITRAL, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Stockholm Lecture, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Stockholm - Background Material-Ethics, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Streamlining Arbitral Proceedings - Some Techniques of the Iran-US Claims Tribunal", 1995 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Study of the Relative Dramatic Playwrights Aeschylus, Sophocles, and Euripides", undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Summary of Remarks by Howard M. Holtzmann, Alternative Representative of the United States at United Nations Commission on International Trade Law Tenth Session, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Tweedle-CONF, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - The Use of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules in Cases Involving State Parties, 2006 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - UNCITRAL - Notes on Organizing Arbitral Proceedings, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - UNCITRA Model Law in Action, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Untitled Holograph, MS, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Untitled Lecture, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Untitled MS, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - What an Arbitrator Can Do to Overcome Delays in International Arbitration, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Whether, When, Where and How to Arbitrate in International Cases, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - The Wound and the Bow, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Yale Lectures, 2011-2012 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Yale B24, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "The Yale '42 Story - 50 Years Out", 1992 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Writings By Others, 1934-2013; 3
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    This subseries contains the manuscripts and typescripts of writings, primarily articles and book chapters, written by people other than Holtzmann.
    - Ajibola, Bola, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Gold, Charlotte, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Higgins, Francis J., William G. Brown, and Patrick J. Roach, undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Knott, De. T.A., 1934 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Reisman, Michael, 2013 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Silkenat, James R., 1990 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Straus, Donald (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Straus, Michael, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - van Berg, Jill, 2004 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Offprints, 1969-2005 (Box 45, Folder 20, Box 46, Folder 1-3)
- Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, 1981-2009; III; 8.95 Cubic Feet 19 legal document boxes
  The material in this series documents Judge Holtzmann's extensive work as the senior US member of the Iran-US Claims Tribunal from its convening in 1981 through 1994. Included are correspondence, chronological files, official documents, memos, communiques, personal notes, and drafts of rulings and resoultions from the Tribunal. Also contained here is a substantial Index to Issues that outlines the various claims and rules covered by the Tribunal.
  - Administrative Directive No. 2 - Tribunal Rules, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Analysis of Decisions - Volume I and II, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 5-7)
  - Annual Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
  - Appointment to Tribunal - Official Letter, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Appointment to Tribunal - Press Release, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Appointment Letters, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - CVs and Resumes - General, 1981-1988 (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - CVs and Resumes - Mosk, Richard M., 1958 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - CVs and Resumes - Non-Current Materials, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Desired Qualifications of Arbitrators to be Selected, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Individuals no longer under Active Consideration, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Legal Assistants - General, 1988-1993 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Legal Assistants - Former, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - List of Initial Arbitrators, undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Meetings to Appoint Remaining Arbitrators, HMH Notes, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Arbitrators and Other Tribunal Personnel - Resignation Letter, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Bibliographies - Legal Writing Concerning United States and Iranian Relations Since the Revolution with a Particular Focus on the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies - List of Publications on the Tribunal, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Boalt Tribunal Material Preliminary Finding Aid, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Cases and Awards - Awards with Opinions, Correction and Amendments by Award Numbers, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. A11, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - A15, A24, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. A33, 2004-2005 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. A3, A8, A9, A14, B6`, 1996-2009 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. A/15, A/26. A/43, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. B1, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 93, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 102, 103, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 103-121, 1993-1994 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 148, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 385, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 457, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 485, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 4-7)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 526-538, 1991-1992 (Box 49, Folder 8, Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 539-548, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 2-4)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 549-555, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 5, Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 556-559, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 823, 1999-2000 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Cases and Awards - Cases - No. 946, 2003 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Challenge to Judge Krzysztof Skubiszewski, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Files, 1993-1994 (Box 51, Folder 6-7, Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Composition of Tribunal 2 - Notecard Summaries of Prospective Arbitrators, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Composition of Tribunal 2 - Persons Considered for Appointment to Tribunal, 1983-1993 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
  - Composition of Tribunal 2 - Prospects, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - General, 1981-2007 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Bahrain, 1994-2005 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Congratulatory Letters re: Tribunal Appointment, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Jaguar Sale, 1991-1994 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Draft Rules - Vol. 1, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
  - Draft Rules - Vol. 2, 1981-1983 (Box 53, Folder 7, Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - Draft Rules - Vol. 3 - Notes, 1981-1984 (Box 54, Folder 3-5)
  - Draft Rules - Article 13 (15) - Mosk Rule, 2000 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Early History, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Final Rules of Procedure, 1983 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Full Tribunal Materials - Chamber 1, 1995-1997 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Full Tribunal Materials - Chamber 2, 1995-1997 (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
  - Full Tribunal Materials - Chamber 3, 1995-1997 (Box 55, Folder 4-5, Box 56, Folder 1-2)
  - Given by U.S. Arbitrators to Iranian Arbitrators, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - HMH Dissenting Opinions, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Index to Issues - Annex, 1981-1993 (Box 56, Folder 5-6, Box 57, Folder 1-2)
  - Index to Issues - Vol. I, 1987-1991 (Box 57, Folder 3-5, Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Index to Issues - Vol. II, 1987-1991 (Box 58, Folder 2-5)
  - Index to Issues - Vol. III, 1987-1991 (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
  - The Lighter Side - Correspondence, Notes, Drafts, 1984-1991 (Box 59, Folder 5, Box 60, Folder 1-4)
  - The Lighter Side - Final Drafts, 1991 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Memos - General, 1982-1996 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Memos - Land Act References, 1986-1997 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Memos - Neuhaus Memo, 1991 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Mosk Rule Cases, 1993-1998 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1981-1987 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material - General, 1981-1994 (Box 61, Folder 6-7)
  - Printed Material - "Articles re: Tribunal", 1990-1993 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material - Clippings, Scrapbook, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Printed Material - News Items, Newspapers, Magazines, FBIs, all Relating to Iran or the Tribunal, 1981-1994 (Box 62, Folder 3-6)
  - Printed Material - Research Materials, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Procedural Rules - Volume I, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 8, Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Procedural Rules - Volume II, 1981-1984 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Research Notes, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Roadmap, 2007 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Significant Orders - Chronological, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
  - Significant Orders - Thematic Digest of Significant Orders, Volume I-II, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 7, Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Stockholm-Iran, 2001-2002 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Tribunal Rules, undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Writings - Brower, Charles N. - Resolution Outside the National Legal Process: The Iran-US Claims Tribunal, 1990-1993 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Writings - Caron, David, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Writings - Holtzmann and Richard Allison - The Tribunal's Use of Experts, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Writings - Iseman, Joseph - Nine Months on a Flying Carpet, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Writings - Nasser, Ibrahim b. Abdulla - The Position of Islamic Shariah towards Banks, 1990-1993 (Box 64, Folder 8)
- United Nations Commission on International Trade Law, 1974-2011; IV; 18.42 Cubic Feet 37 legal document boxes and 1 oversize flat box
  This series includes material pertaining to Holtzmann's time as a US delegate to UNCITRAL, and includes correspondence, working group papers, conference and seminar materials, research materials, writings, and numerous draft documents of arbitration rules. The latter material includes final versions of arbitration rules and model laws, as well as early versions, correspondence relating to their drafting, and corrected drafts and commentary on the rules.
  Primarily arranged by record type and alphabetically. Session and working group materials are arranged by session number and date. Arbitration rule drafts are arranged by rule number.
  - American Arbitration Association, 2002 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - American Bar Association - Revisions - Correspondence, 2009-2010 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - American Bar Association - Panel, 2009-2010 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration Rules - Arrangements, 2009 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 0, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 1-9, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 2-4, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 2-4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 5, 1975-2001 (Box 65, Folder 5-10)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 6, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 7, 1975-2001 (Box 65, Folder 12, Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 8, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 9-13, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 3-8)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 13-19, 1975-2006 (Box 67, Folder 1-7)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 21-27, 1975-1976 (Box 67, Folder 8, Box 68, Folder 1-2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 28-40, 1975-1976 (Box 68, Folder 3-5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Article Drafts - 31-41, 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Addendum Concerning Adoption of UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules to Report of the United States Delegation, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Background Material for Detailed Drafting Suggestions, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Checklist of Drafting Suggestions, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Comments - Comments and Suggested Modifications Proposed by United States Delegation, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Rules - Comments - Comments on Preliminary Draft of UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Arbitration Rules - Comments - Pieter Sanders, undated (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Arbitration Rules - Comments - USA Comments on 1976 Draft (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Arbitration Rules - Comments - Corporate Counsel Meeting - HMH Report on UNCITRAL, undated (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration Rules - Draft of Digest of Clout Cases, 1993-2004 (Box 70, Folder 1-3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Expert Group - General, 1999-2005 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Expert Group - Arrangements, 1993-2001 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Expert Group - Conciliation Background for June 2002 Commission Meeting (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Expert Group - Excerpt from Secretariat Paper for Expert Group, 1999 December (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Form Sheet Originals, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Rules - General Assembly - "Some Notes", 2000-2005 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Instructions-Work Sheets, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Introductory Rules, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Article 0, 40 and 41, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Article 1, undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Background Materials and Superseded Drafts, 2004-2008 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Draft Compilation and Analysis of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume 1, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Draft Compilation and Analysis of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume 2, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 3-4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Draft Compilation and Analysis of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume 3, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 5-6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Draft Compilation and Analysis of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume 4, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 7, Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Final Text as Adopted, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - General Observation on Rules, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Historical Background on Rules, 1974-1976 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume I, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 5-6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume II, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules - Volume 3, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 3-5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Proposal re: Articles 1-21, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Legislative History - Report of Committee II, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Rules - Maritime Arbitration, 2005-2006 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Master Sheets, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 2-4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Model Clause, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Rules - New York Convention, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Part II, undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Preliminary Draft, 1974 April (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Preliminary Draft - Session 8, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 4-7, Box 77, Folder 1-2)
  - Arbitration Rules - Preliminary Draft - Proposal for Including Preliminary Orders in the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration Rules - Proposal for the Mexican Government, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Requirement of Written Form for Arbitration Agreement, 1999 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Rules - Revisions - Comments of the UK on the Revised Draft, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Rules - Revisions - Revised Draft for 13th Session, 1980 (Box 77, Folder 7-8, Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Revisions - Revision of the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 2006-2008 (Box 78, Folder 2-4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Revisions Materials, 1975-2009 (Box 78, Folder 5-11)
  - Arbitration Rules - Richard D. Kearney Draft, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Arbitration Rules - Secretarial Draft, WP 138, paragraph 4, 2005 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Rules - Vis Draft, 1975 September-October (Box 79, Folder 2-4)
  - Arbitration Rules - Worksheet, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Canada Proposal, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Cases Discussing New York Convention, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Castello, James - UNCITRAL Rules, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
  - Center for International Environmental Law, 2008 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - CISG Advisory Council, 2004 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - CLOUT and Digests, undated (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Comments Concerning Draft Federal Law for the Year 2006, Concerning International Arbitration (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Commercial Arbitration and Other Alternative Dispute Resolution Methods, 2001 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Conciliation - General, 1976 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Conciliation - AAA, 2001 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Conciliation - Background Materials, 2000 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Conciliation - China, 2000 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Conciliation - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Conciliation - Documents, undated (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Conciliation - Model Conciliation Law - General, 2001-2003 (Box 80, Folder 4-6)
  - Conciliation - Model Conciliation Law - Report, 2002 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Conciliation - Organization of the Conciliation Binder, 2000-2002 (Box 81, Folder 2-6)
  - Conciliation - PCA Conciliation Rules, 1992-2000 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
  - Conciliation - Sanders - PCA Suggestions, 2000-2002 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Conciliation - Statutes, 1999 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - General, 2003-2011 (Box 82, Folder 5-6, Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Liability for Wrongfully Obtained Interim Measures, 2003-2004 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Transport Convention, 2006 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Corporate Counsel Committee, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Governance Program, 2003-2006 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Draft Questionnaire on the Practical Aspects of Using Commercial Arbitration in the UN-ECE Region, 2000 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Social Council, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Electronic Commerce, 2004 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Enclosure to the Memorandum, 1996 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - European Commission - Draft Directive and Mediation, 2004 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - ICCA Matters, 1980 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Interim Measures - General, 1999-2005 (Box 83, Folder 12-13)
  - Interim Measures - 36th Form, 2002 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Interim Measures - Abscal Questions, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Interim Measures - Background Material, 2000-2003 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Interim Measures - Cecil Branson Comment, 2002 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Interim Measures - Commentary on Draft, 2006 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Interim Measures - Correspondence, 2002-2006 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Interim Measures - Drafting Notes, 2002 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Interim Measures - Enforcement, 2001 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Interim Measures - Ex Parte, 2003-2004 (Box 84, Folder 7-10)
  - Interim Measures - Interim Measures and Written Form - Extra and Complete Documents, 2002 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Interim Measures - Power of Tribunal, undated (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Interim Measures - Printed Material, 2006 (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - Interim Measures - Supporting Documents, 2005-2006 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Interim Measures - Written Form, 1996-2001 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Law Reform Committee, 2009 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Limitations on Reports and Summary Rewards, 2004 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous - Secretarial Notes, Agendas, 2006-2008 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Model Clause, 1980 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Model Law - On International Commercial Arbitration, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Model Law - Neuhaus Revisions, 2010-2011 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Notes - General, undated (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Notes - On Organizing Arbitral Proceedings, 1993-1996 (Box 85, Folder 10-11, Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 2005 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Origin, Mandate and Composition, 1998 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - PCA - General, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - PCA - Take to Vienna, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Politically Incorrect Bedtime Stories, 1994 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material - General, 1998-2008 (Box 86, Folder 7-8)
  - Printed Material - Journal of the United Nations, 1976-2001 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material - Model Law on International Commercial Conciliation with Guide to Enactment and Use, 2002 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Printed Material - New Thinking on Developments in International Commercial Arbitration - Developments at UNCITRAL, 2005 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Printed Material - Recent Practice-Future Possibilities: A Survey of Practitioners in International Commercial Arbitration, 2005 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material - Reference Material, 2003-2004 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material - Reports, 1999-2006 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material - United Nations Convention on the Use of Electronic Communications in International Contracts, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Printed Material - UNCITRAL, Second Edition, undated (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Publications by and UNCITRAL: Sources and Availability, 1998 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Re: UNCITRAL at ICCA Meeting, 1993 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Report of the Secretariat, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Reports of US Delegation, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Sanders, Pieter - UNCITRAL's Model Law on International and Commercial Arbitration, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Sixth UNCITRAL Symposium, 1995 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Speech in Sixth Committee, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - State Department Advisory Committee - Working Group on Arbitration - Full Commission, 2000 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - States of UNCITRAL Conventions and Model Laws, 2000 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Study Group on Arbitration - US Department of State, 2000 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - United Nations, 1994-1995 (Box 88, Folder 9)